Enjoy Simple English 森崎ウィンです
毎週木曜日は2019年度に放送した
古典が語る西洋の知恵をお送りしています
ギリシャ神話Greek Mythから
西洋の表現や考えなどを学びます
今回はNarcissusです
自分のことが好きな人のことを言う
日本語のナルシストの語源になった話です
では早速聞いてみましょう
ナーシシスの花を知っていますか?
日本の名前はスイセンです
花の名前はグリークの秘密から出てきます
ここからお話しします
ナーシシスはかわいい若い男で
たくさんの女の子が彼を愛していました
でもナーシシスは誰もを愛していませんでした
一日
a girl's heart was broken by narcissus she cried and prayed to the gods
i hope that he will fall in love with someone someday but that person will not love him
then he will understand my feelings
a goddess heard her and said i heard your prayer
I will make it come true
One day, Narcissus was hunting in the forest
and he became very hot and thirsty
Suddenly, he found a spring
The water was like silver
and the surface was very clean
There were no fallen leaves and branches in the water
Narcissus saw the spring and thought
I am lucky. I will drink some water from it.
Then he saw a very handsome young man in the water.
He thought,
It must be a water spirit.
Oh, look at those eyes.
They are so bright.
And look at its curly hair.
It is as beautiful as the gods Bacchus and Apollo.
Everything is beautiful.
パーフェクト
それは水の霊ではなく、彼の自分の反応ではありませんでした
でもナーシシスはこれを知らなかったので、彼は考えた
私は、愛に恋を持っていると考えています
ナーシシスはそれを触って、水に手を伸ばしました
それが、水に手を伸ばしたときに逃げ出たのです
そして、その後、戻ってきたのです
He tried many times, but he couldn't touch it.
Narcissus forgot about eating and sleeping.
He only thought about the image in the spring.
He spoke to it.
Why do you keep away from me?
Many people love me, and you seem to love me.
You smile when I smile.
You reach out your arms when I do.
ナーシシスはとても悲しかった。
そして彼の涙が春の中に落ちてしまった。
写真が消えてしまった。
ナーシシスは言った。
私はあなたが私を愛していないことを理解している。
でも、
私はあなたを見てみようとした。
そのため、ナーシシスは春の中に落ちて、
彼は彼を見ていた。
ナーシシスは弱くて弱くなった。
そして、
彼は亡くなった。
ニンフは彼を葬儀したが、彼の身体を見つけられなかった。
春に美しい白い花を見つけたのです。
なぜその花の名前を知っているのか、
水面に映る自分の顔を見て恋に落ちてしまった
ハンサムな若者をナルシスティス
すごいね
でもねちょっとだけ気持ちわかる
おめかしした後おーいいねってあるじゃないですか
そんな自分のこと大好きな人を表現する言葉
ナルシスティス
ナルシストっていう単語が生まれましたね
See you tomorrow